NAME
    gcloud auth - manage oauth2 credentials for the Google Cloud CLI

SYNOPSIS
    gcloud auth GROUP | COMMAND [GCLOUD_WIDE_FLAG ...]

DESCRIPTION
    The gcloud auth command group lets you grant and revoke authorization to
    Google Cloud CLI (gcloud CLI) to access Google Cloud. Typically, when
    scripting Google Cloud CLI tools for use on multiple machines, using gcloud
    auth activate-service-account is recommended.

    For information about authorization and credential types, see Authorizing
    the gcloud CLI (https://cloud.google.com/sdk/docs/authorizing). For
    information about authorizing a service account, see Authorizing with a
    service account
    (https://cloud.google.com/sdk/docs/authorizing#service-account).

    After running gcloud auth commands, you can run other commands with
    --account=ACCOUNT to authenticate the command with the credentials of the
    specified account. For information about --account and other gcloud CLI
    global flags, see the gcloud CLI overview
    (https://cloud.google.com/sdk/gcloud/reference).

    See $ gcloud topic client-certificate to learn how to use Mutual TLS when
    using gcloud. Mutual TLS can be used for certificate based access
    (https://cloud.google.com/beyondcorp-enterprise/docs/securing-resources-with-certificate-based-access)
    with gcloud.

EXAMPLES
    To authenticate a user account with gcloud and minimal user output, run:

        $ gcloud auth login --brief

    To list all credentialed accounts and identify the current active account,
    run:

        $ gcloud auth list

    To revoke credentials for a user account (like logging out), run:

        $ gcloud auth revoke test@gmail.com

GCLOUD WIDE FLAGS
    These flags are available to all commands: --help.

    Run $ gcloud help for details.

GROUPS
    GROUP is one of the following:

     application-default
        Manage your active Application Default Credentials.

     enterprise-certificate-config
        Manage enterprise certificate configurations.

COMMANDS
    COMMAND is one of the following:

     activate-service-account
        Authorize access to Google Cloud with a service account.

     configure-docker
        Register gcloud as a Docker credential helper.

     list
        Lists credentialed accounts.

     login
        Authorize gcloud to access the Cloud Platform with Google user
        credentials.

     print-access-token
        Print an access token for the specified account.

     print-identity-token
        Print an identity token for the specified account.

     revoke
        Revoke access credentials for an account.

NOTES
    This variant is also available:

        $ gcloud beta auth

